[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
me
knowledge is power
[Music]
excellent ladies and gentlemen welcome
to the junkyard love podcast today i'm
here with josh gebhardt
hello josh how are you today buddy hey
i'm good thanks thanks for having me on
yeah yeah i'm super pumped that you
agreed to come on i am
i mean i i've been friends with you guys
for a while but i just i downright
admire you guys
i mean you guys as in you and your
sisters and your friend group
um we all met up at uh we met at a music
festival
what was like 2012 or 13 or something
a while back for sure it's been many
years yeah
yeah so i mean i always i feel like we
just we've had so many good times
together um so yeah i really appreciate
you
agreeing to come on and kind of just bs
with me today josh
awesome i'm excited to be here yeah so
um let's just start with like what have
you been up to the last year or so you
know obviously
everybody's lives have changed pretty
dramatically
in many ways um since covet and whatnot
so
what what's your what's your like last
year been looking like what you been
doing
yeah i would say last year um you know
despite as crazy as it was and all of
the
you know bad stuff going on and i think
for me personally it was a really good
year
um i um bought a house um with my
partner recently so that's been really
exciting being a first-time homebuyer
and so a lot of our focus was preparing
for that obviously financially and we
did that
right before the end of the year so a
lot of the year was preparing for that
so i think
um having everything on lockdown was a
positive for me because i wasn't
spending money on traveling or going out
all the time so um
for me that was a good that was good to
help me get to my goal faster of getting
into a house
um and then now that we've been in here
we're just really focusing on new
furniture and decorating and all that
stuff so
um that occupies most of my time i would
say um
and then career-wise i had a successful
year i mean
i'm a director of sales at a software
company and um
despite all the things that were thrown
at us um we sell travel
solutions to companies and so obviously
no one was traveling so
there was a lot of um a lot of having to
really like adapt and pivot and
really show kind of resiliency in terms
of how we approached how we were going
to get to our numbers and
um i was really happy i got you know
five out of the excuse me four of the
six people that worked for me got
promoted this year
so anytime as a leader you're able to
help people kind of get to that
next step um and their career is really
exciting so i'm happy to
help them get there and um i finished
you know um
achieving president's club despite how
crazy the year was so
um a lot to be proud of and a lot to be
really appreciative and grateful of um
as well so a lot of turmoil kind of like
all around us but i think
you know was able to um you know
kind of you know find my way through it
i guess right right i mean huge congrats
on the house that's so cool you guys got
a house like
i i've seen a couple photos and stuff
but i can't wait to see it in person
um excuse me and then also can you
explain president's club what what is
that
oh yeah so president's club is
essentially if you achieve over 130
percent of your quota
then you qualify um then you qualify to
go on a trip so they you get like an
award and then they take you on a trip
somewhere so
last year's was in maui which was
cancelled because of covid
um and then rescheduled for october but
then was canceled again
um so now we are the next one coming up
will be um it's supposed to be in mexico
um next year so
we'll see how that goes and if we're
able to go but um it's more so
just for like the pride of achieving it
basically just trying to finish in the
top you know group of all the
salespeople or sales leaders and so
um it's kind of like what you fight for
all year so it's um kind of a benchmark
of if you had a successful year
right okay okay i know you've worked
you've worked for this company for quite
a while now how many years is it
um over eight years now which is so
crazy so i think
when we first met i think i was like
really newly
working there um when we first met so i
think
i was around the same time or maybe in
the first two years of being here i feel
like i remember you always killing it at
this job though like
you've just been hitting the ground
running since the beginning
yeah i mean i've had a really successful
here and really like grateful for that
um and it's kind of interesting i think
kind of like ties into some of the stuff
that we thought we might discuss today
too is i think you know for me
my job and my career has really served
as like a really important part of
um just like my self-confidence and how
i think about myself i really found
like i think purpose also in it and
which is interesting to find
purpose in a corporate job um
where it can be very not purposeful or
not purpose driven
um and i think that go like the purpose
that i found in this
number one i found something that i
think i was naturally good at and have a
natural kind of you know tendency just
to
excel at which obviously when you find
something that you do well i think it
helps you feel better about yourself
right when you when you experience
success
um but then being there for so many
years and transitioning into a
leadership role and leading others
i love now getting to guide or support
or
aid other people and them finding
their native genius or what their
strengths are i'm in their job in
helping them
exceed or excel and build up their
confidence and then help kind of send
them off to the next
point in their career um and
specifically the part of the market that
we sell into
um because we sell the small businesses
we're typically working with people who
it's like their first or second job out
of college
they probably don't have a lot of kind
of professional experience maybe they've
done an internship or they have some
entry-level
kind of experience but they've never
really done a true formal quota caring
sales job
and so i love that part of my job
because every two three years i'm kind
of turning over the team it's new people
so it's constantly changing but i think
that's such an important part of
someone's life they're a young adult
entering the corporate workforce or
getting their first you know kind of
really a real adult job
and so um that's where i find like the
purposeful part of what i do and that
like fulfills me
where like i could just you know
obviously hitting a number and making
money is great but like that's the part
of my job where
i really like get my joy from i guess if
that makes sense
yeah no dude i really like that i really
so i want to talk about purpose for sure
but i think um
something that i notice about you just
by being a friend i haven't worked with
you in this environment but i think that
um because i had wanted to talk to you
about your own self-confidence like your
own belief in yourself
and um it's it's ecstatic it's like a
you have a good ability to actually like
allow other people to bring out the
confidence in themselves
just by you being your authentic self um
and i can imagine i love how you tie
that into like it's purposeful
you know you're actually you're stepping
in the role of the leader
and you get to train these people you
get to teach them what you've
been through so i love that but uh as
far as purpose
i think that's an interesting one
because i me
as a like i identify as a creator
a lot or just like an artistic person um
and i i find trouble i i have trouble
finding purpose in things that aren't
like my own art it's like this
weird selfish gets in my own way sort of
thing
but it's hard for me to apply um purpose
to like working for
another company or working doing
something for someone else this totally
sounds
selfish but um i think that's could we
can we expand more on that like
what do you mean by purpose what what
does it really feel like to you
yeah i think um you know you bring up a
great point i think it is hard to know
like
working in my industry to you it's like
i could say well i feel that i have you
know the skills and the talents i could
go you know start my own company i could
be an entrepreneur i could start a
business tomorrow or
create a startup or have an idea you
know um but i think number one what you
do takes a lot more courage
than something like what i do right
because i kind of tore the line of
i could go do those things they could
take those risks but do i have the
courage to really do it so
um you know i i think that's what it
makes everyone really interested in
dynamics like i respect that quality in
you
so much um but what i mean by purpose is
i think that
um at the point in someone's career that
i get the opportunity to work with them
as i do think that is so pivotal right
like i think about like
what happens in that first couple years
outside of college
is really going to be something that
really is a life-defining moment like
it's gonna probably not
be defining in terms of um you know the
most important part of your life but
what i do is i think it's like one of
those really
big forks in the road where it's gonna
like whatever happens in that couple
years and it's gonna
probably put you on a trajectory or a
path where you're probably going to go
for the next several years
right so like let's say for example if
you get in and you don't do well
you're probably going to change
industries or change career paths right
so
it's really interesting where if you can
help people do that so
um again being in this little window i
get i feel like i really got to help
kind of like guide people and
get them on the right path and you know
sometimes that's helping them exceed
what we do and helping them move on
and move up in the company and sometimes
it's showing them that this is not meant
for them and helping hold up the mirror
to them and saying like
are you really happy here it you know i
because i can't imagine working in a
sales environment where you're not
successful and
or you don't maybe align with the
corporate values you're maybe not a
person who
is really feels like you want to push
the customer to buy more
you know buy something additional like
that's not maybe that doesn't align with
your core values but maybe you ended up
in this job because you thought it was
you know a good thing and so i've had to
help people have you know find those
things too
um and kind of help find them on their
path and sometimes that's helping them
look outside of the company so um that's
what i mean by that
makes me feel purposeful that makes me
feel good about myself like when i can
wake up make a difference in someone's
like life you know
and with work we don't really think of
it that
like emotionally or like that um that
much in depth you should kind of surface
level it's my boss it's whatever
but um i think if you were to ask you
know any of the people who've been a
part of the teams that i've been lucky
enough to
be a part of it's like that they truly
do feel like families
um though they really they are like my
brothers i've had
mostly um men that have worked for me
and we typically create like a really
strong brotherhood where we stay in
touch after we work together for a long
time so
um it's a i don't know it's just a
really um a really special part of my
life and a really
special component that i know adds so
much value to it um in a lot of
different ways
yeah i love that i imagine the
environment to be to be just wonderful i
mean i've heard like hearing their
stories and and you know seeing photos
and whatnot but
that would be really cool to work for
someone who um
like really sees you kind of as as a
person and like hey
is this what you want to do you know not
just you're not just looking out for
yourself here you're not just looking
out for numbers here you're trying to
figure out
um is this something you could see or
see yourself doing for an extended
period of time
i think that's really important um your
your experience
before working here um you didn't you
didn't go to school did you
i didn't which um you know kind of
thinking about
that has always served as probably like
one of the biggest pieces of insecurity
that i do have
um like a lot of my social circle or a
lot of people that i
work with now professionally i'm
probably one of the only
maybe like i've met one other person
really that doesn't have a college
degree
um that does kind of like what i do or
works really in our industry it's just
kind of more
common that everyone does and so
especially in my first couple years
working at the company i was like really
insecure about it
and um you know because that's always
like especially
in like a corporate setting that's
always everyone's first like
small talk entry-level thing like in an
interview everyone's like
oh you're a husky oh you're coog it's
like i've been in like
dozens and dozens of interviews where
it's like that's what i'm talking about
i'm like
and those are just funny things too like
those are just like um
you know like invisible by like um
unconscious bias that we have right too
like
where they don't realize that or they
don't know you don't know like what kind
of like
um zone that that puts like an
interviewee in right when you're talking
about that and they might not have that
same thing to
connect on but i was always really
insecure about that but now
um i feel like my career has kind of
like replaced that
and so to myself i feel like i've earned
my stripes and i'm really proud to be
where i am and
um happy you know almost sometimes can
be more proud that i did it without the
degree because that makes it harder in a
lot of ways but
um not going to school was definitely
something that i always kind of like
wish that i did and was kind of hard to
myself
about um but i think everything worked
out okay so i'm i'm not against it and
it's always something that is there if i
really wanted to go back and
approach it again um but when i think
about like my
individuality and kind of like the way
that i view myself in a lot of my life
experience that i've gotten
um i got when i didn't go to college so
i think
when a lot of people discover themselves
or start to learn like peel back the
layers of who they are
and who they want to be um and just like
a lot of those life experiences right
like
in relationships and friendships and
being on your own
um i didn't really get that in the
traditional sense of going away to
college or going away for four years
um and so but one thing that i that i
kind of reflect or can kind of
um compare my experience to is
i was doing a job for i was working for
bank of america at the time
and i got um i was chosen to go and be a
part
of um their transformation team which
is where basically they were converting
the computer systems in the state of
california
and so um long story short i was living
in california
for a temporary work assignment and i
went there
and i was in an apartment that the
company put me in i didn't know a single
person i was 21
and i but i was there by myself and i
was
you know discovering like my you know
really being open with my sexuality for
the first time but
it was the first time that i felt
comfortable doing so
because i wasn't home right like i
wasn't in my hometown i wasn't i was
around my citrus i wasn't around my
friends
so on one side i was so excited to just
go and be completely kind of like
liberated in the sense of i can go walk
around or go to a barn
go experience things or try things out
or see what i like
or you know i'm interested in this one
thing or what like
am i gonna like that environment or
whatever it is right so i had the
ability to go really be really curious
but i also had the chance to be myself
without any
like any baggage of who you think you
are the way that you grow up or who
you're around or
pressures that you think you know the
people you might hurt the people around
you to be your authentic self or
whatever that might be
so that was really freeing and really
liberating for me and then at the same
time
it also i you know moved away from a
small town in monroe
um washington and then was able to go be
there
and i didn't know anybody at all right
so it was my first time i would go to
like a bar
and i would go and i have to like like i
would prep i'd give myself a pep talk on
the way like in the car
and i'd be like okay you're gonna go to
the bar you're going by yourself you
don't have a single friend you don't
know a single person in
in la you have to go and be like
have the ability to go like start a
conversation with someone like face to
face and so like
i would do that like i would go to
dinner by myself i would go to a bar and
i would just go
and like approach people and so um i
think it was really uncomfortable
it's not definitely not fun um at first
but
you know i think like forcing myself to
do that really taught me
a lot about just kind of like confidence
and not being like afraid of people
um and just being willing to like take
the risk and say like whatever like
obviously i'm sure there's not every
person that like i tried to strike a
connection with
obviously doesn't happen but you know
you find you know you find people or
you also can really connect with someone
that shows you some sort of like
openness or friendship or warmth
back in response then you're like it
just kind of like instantly can
like spark joy for you or show you like
that people are good and then you know
those are how great friendships begin
those are how great adventures begin and
so
there's so many people that i met and
connected with that were really
impactful
um during that time in my life too and
that people that i'm still friends with
today too so
um i think that was kind of for me like
my
quote unquote college experience of like
getting to go be there and do that and i
think that really transformed me a lot
too
right yeah you kind of put yourself
through the like the social side of
college
of i mean i imagine you're going through
these pep talks like you and your car
like all right
let's go or you're looking in the mirror
like at a hotel just
you got to meet people you got to talk
to them make eye contact you know like
that's powerful though man that's that's
i mean that's really how you make it
real connections and
challenging yourself to step outside of
your your comfort zone
and um i mean i think when i
i remember because i grew up in fairly
small town
um kelso washington and
it was kind of the same thing for me i
didn't move away but i started traveling
um even for like wadeca and then uh
for like audio and stuff or live events
uh soon after
and i remember there was just this thing
that i i didn't realize that had been
there before
but uh like your assumptions would have
of what everybody is thinking about you
by
staying in your same town it's kind of
like you're walking around in high
school and you're kind of stuck to your
avatar of
whatever your you're you like whatever
click you're in and wherever you stand
with it you actually have that in your
town
i remember when i went to places like
bellevue even
not even that far it's three hours away
and i just
felt more open like i feel like my my
chest opened up
i felt like i was um more confident in
myself
my when i would meet people you know i
felt fine shaking their hand more firmly
look at them in the eye these sorts of
things and
i imagine the the doors that this opens
compared to you know kind of being in
our shell
you know maybe staying on our phones not
challenging ourselves to do these
like potentially like you might
introduce yourself and make a fool out
of yourself
and then you got three people who are
just like making fun of you or something
i mean
unlikely but that's that's pretty
powerful man i i think that that's
not a skill that everybody um
not not that it's a skill that you were
born with so to say like you definitely
have sharp into that because you weren't
always here
but i think a lot of people would
benefit even from just hearing you talk
about that
yeah um yeah i know absolutely and then
i think you know
coming back from that like from that you
know temporary
um you know time of being there then
when i came back i think i was
not like a changed person at my core of
who i was what my values are the type of
person that i was
i think i came back like i said like
with a lot of
with a lot of like weight off of me i
had a lot more confidence a lot more
like swagger and my stuff and just
a lot more self-assurance of who i was
and i was more proud of who i was
um because i found in making connections
with
with strangers or people in a new town
of new people that like people liked me
and they liked me
there when i took off the baggage of who
i thought i was supposed to be or
my own light or carrying the burdens of
you know
um you know of anything of your past
right or just
you know anything like that so and i
realized that people were more drawn
to me and i um i was naturally becoming
more magnetic to the right type of
people that i wanted to be around
and so then when i returned to seattle
and came home
um i definitely you know got back into
like a lot of my old friendships but at
the same time i was still kind of really
craving that ability to kind of like
keep stepping out keep experiencing new
things
um you know keep uh meeting new people
um and then what was funny in turn two
is i think that
once i had like once i came back and had
that like renewed sense of self
it's funny like i think also people from
my past who maybe i didn't have the best
relationship or dynamic with it's almost
like i felt like
they were then maybe people let me be
more clear people that maybe i felt like
i didn't know where i stood with them or
i wasn't sure of how our friendship was
um or how they perceived me or maybe i
felt a little bit insecure about my my
friendships or relationships or dynamics
with certain people
people that i felt like maybe i was a
little bit more not chasing but
felt maybe like lesser than in my own
mind or was i cool enough or was i good
enough or do i fit in with them
when i came back and i had that running
sense of self
those people started to naturally be
come back to me not through my own
efforts
but just because i think that again once
you start
living as you're supposed to live and
being who you're supposed to be
i think you're not like the authentic or
the authenticity that you display
and exhibit and demonstrate are it's
going to be what naturally brings people
back to you
um and so it i thought that was like
really interesting too because that was
a
an outcome or a result that i had never
planned on or never saw really happening
but it was really and i think that also
compounded
my confidence in saying look the more
that i'm myself the more that i'm
authentic the more that i accept myself
the more that
people around me are going to be
attracted to me because it is real it is
genuine it is honest
um and so i thought that was like a
really interesting kind of thing to
experience and see as well
yeah that's super powerful i like how
you tied in authenticity with your
confidence i feel like that's totally
what it is
i mean it's just like i was saying when
you're confident like me
just as your friend you encourage me to
be more authentic when i'm
when i'm around you like just because
you are naturally that way like your
confidence just
has a as an aroma you know it just it
just comes off and people around you are
are also confident i think that's that's
pretty powerful stuff
um when it comes to authenticity let's
switch over to social media
so i i'm always like because again like
trying to present myself as an artist or
like a
i'm a dj and i have like this like
character that i kind of have to play on
stage in some senses you know it's
almost like an act or
um like like on the podcast i want to
like my thing i want to be authentic
like not that i want to like
tell all my deepest darkest like fears
and just like make sure that's on there
every episode or anything
but i i want to show up as myself but
then there's also this part of me that
um like changes like this makes you a
good host let's make sure you're
um doing these different things like
it's
i think that social media and um even
our our work
like the things that we do they kind of
become extensions
of who we are or like almost like a
a trained delicate part of our ego like
our
um our identity our identity that we
interact with with everybody else in the
outside world
so what do you think about
when it comes to situations where you're
[Music]
kind of like putting on different
versions of yourself um
but but keeping your authenticity like
so how do you like so say so say you
identify josh as a
like i'm a nice guy it's like it's i
feel in my im like
i not only identify it but i know that
i'm a nice guy but then you have
a meeting at work where you got to be
the guy to fire someone you got to be
the
the bad guy how do you
i guess how do you balance like the
different aspects of our personalities
that have to interact with the outside
world whether that's on social media or
at work or whatever with being truly
authentic does anything pop up to you in
that yeah
um a little bit so i think you know
social media in itself i don't know if
this is directly answering your question
but
social i'm going to give you a direct
question that's okay
i'll pick where i want to dive in here
um i think with social media i think
it's so interesting and
it's ever changing right too i think
like when we met
like when when you and i first met um i
definitely cared
so much more about social media and i
don't know if that is if that's
i definitely care less um but i can tell
myself that i care less because i put
less effort into
like taking pictures and doing the right
thing and trying to like go somewhere
but
i do still have an element of me that
does
want to uh oh actually this is
interesting um
so there this is just brought me brought
me the thought this might be more
interesting
so um with social media there was
definitely a time and i probably still
have elements of this if i'm being
completely honest
um but there are elements of i would try
to do things or achieve a certain amount
of success
financially or materialistically
um to prove that i had somehow
accomplished something or that i was
good enough or
um and a lot of that i read this book um
called the velvet rage which i
really recommend um it's about growing
up gay basically in like you know like a
hetero
world um and it's written by a
psychologist
and there's a couple different kind of
like personality types or archetypes
that you could kind of probably
try to identify with um as a gay person
and when i was reading the book
one of them is someone who basically
tries to overcompensate
with non-emotional things to prove
that they're good enough or that they're
better so like for me like i would
always prove like
a trip that i was gone or somewhere that
i was posting or what designer i was
wearing
i was basically saying like yes i'm gay
but look how successful i am or
look what i've accomplished like well
like you know you can't it's different
than if you want to like insult me and
if i was uh you know
if i wasn't successful or whatever then
i'm gonna take him more but i'm
basically
using all that stuff as like a shield
and armor as it were like a defense
to say like yes i'm gay but look at all
these great things sam so like you can't
really
like come you can't really like judge my
life or because i'm like you know i'm
so and so better than you or i i'm uh or
whatever i'm trying to elevate myself
but it's with things that are not
like that aren't meaningful you know
what i mean yeah oh that's pretty
powerful
yeah so what was the name of that book
uh yeah the velvet rage
um i don't know the name of the author
i'd have to look but the the author is a
psychologist and so
um and then you know there's different
people who who would escape through
you know promiscuity and sex to try to
feel
like to fill a goiter to do all that
right so i think there's different ways
um but i think you know once i learned
that and you know i talked to like you
know people close to me or my sisters i
think you know
they would definitely say like yeah you
definitely have that element of like
you have something to prove kind of in
that sense too
um and so that definitely is an element
of my personality or
the reason i do things or how i make
decisions sometimes it's definitely
based on that i do have like a part of
my ego that definitely drives me to do
those sort of things
right do you know can you recall like
the transition or when you were able to
because now you're looking back at it in
retrospect like oh okay maybe i was
um you know re or posting these certain
things to try to fulfill
something that i that i didn't realize i
was telling myself i didn't have
and of course the book itself probably
changed a lot of that but do you
remember a time when like
when did the actual change happen and i
point that i asked that because
i'm pretty convinced that a lot of
people um because we all have our own
thing like that to some extent
i feel like for sure and a lot of people
i think over the last year because we've
kind of been forced inside and we've
been forced to
to check out our interiors as
individuals
um i think a lot of people are probably
coming to terms with oh
i was doing this to get this or you know
me
just me as an example i i'm definitely
someone who i have
i'm always trying to balance how much
self-validation i'm seeking like how
much validation i'm trying to get by
like oh don't you don't you see me as an
artist or don't you see me as like a
nice podcast guy or whatever whatever it
is um so that exact like that moment of
change
and then were you also were you nice to
yourself about it or were you like
you weren't like embarrassed or anything
like oh i'm so ashamed that i used to do
these things or
no i'm like i'm like a no shame that's a
fault i'm like a no shame person
i was like i'm like there was reasoning
behind that there was some there was the
why behind that
um no so definitely i've i've never
really been a person that's been
too tough by myself and i don't i think
that part of me is natural
um i'm definitely not a person that's
part of myself i'm definitely like a
person that's like
you earned it you deserve it so fair
come on splurge
like whatever it is so i'm indulgent um
and like if i want something i'll get it
i don't like being
told no so i'm not really hard on myself
in that sense um
but you know i think you know i've had a
couple of
situations where you kind of when you
talk about like those pivotal moments or
in reflection is i think that you end up
in either situations or
relationships like friendships or social
settings
and you realize that there's no uh that
there's no
stakes in them there's no there's no
meaning there's no depth right
and then you like you know you might be
like you know they're you might just be
at a party and be like
who like why am i like why am i really
here you're like
oh because i met someone that like or
you know met someone off of instagram or
that i saw someone at a party and like
whatever we connected in but then you're
there like you're like we're not talking
about anything of meaning
these aren't people that i like these
aren't people that if i had them over
that i wouldn't want to kick them out at
like the end of the night
that you know it's not people that i
would want to be around sober and be
watching a movie with on a sunday i can
tell you that much it's not
you know it's like i think they're i
think you end up in situations like that
and you're like
like what am i chasing because they're
cool because they like the way that they
dress or because like they like we like
the same music like
they're in there can be meaning in those
things too but i think like
um ending up in those situations i'm
like i'm the p and then the people that
i truly am closest with that i truly
have
you know vulnerable moments with um
heartfelt conversations
i'm like it's not impressing them and
they're almost seeing
the people that are close to me they
almost see the facade of who you're
trying to be which
probably almost diminishing in turn
those relationships not that they're
gonna like
walk away from you but they're probably
rolling their eyes and saying like
that's not the josh that i know like
who's like
projecting something or trying to be
something or trying to be cool
um that's not who like when i'm with
josh he's a dork he doesn't shut up he's
the person who
would send a text or will send 10 text
messages in a row he's a person who's
like a little annoying he's a little
like
a little over the top so it's like but
then if so it's like they're probably
like questioning like am i being
authentic too and then those people i'm
just kind of like you know
putting on a little bit of a charade
just to like fit in or to just because i
think they're cool like what makes
anyone cool anyways i don't know it's
just such a weird thing but
um but i think the like you know moments
like that make you start to be like
you're the things that you post for
social media are never typically for
you you're not when you do it in your
subconscious i don't think we're
thinking about
what it's like you know i don't think
about like what is bringing cooley gonna
say what does you know what is um
what are my best friends on my group
check and say what am i sister
understand i'm thinking like i wonder
like if there's like one of like these
random people like what's their
their impression can they give me right
so we're kind of like think i know i
don't think
i think that's an interesting way of how
we look at what we post and what we
present or what we put out there
yeah yeah cause we do kind of like try
to paint this this corner of ourselves
you know i mean it's
at this point we've had social media
long enough now it's not like we're
we're blind to it anymore
like everybody knows oh okay this is our
highlight reel
like this isn't i feel like there was a
first few few years
of social media where it was just kind
of blind to a lot of us we didn't really
realize what we were doing
me for sure um i remember i had i had
photo
um i wanted to like i wanna i wanna find
the photo and like put them side by side
but i had a photo where i went out um
with a
photo shoot with my friend and i
actually photoshopped
like my bicep to be a little bit bigger
in the photo
yeah and like it was weird because i as
i was doing it like it never occurred
like it was like oh yeah
i'm making the photo look cooler like i
put them side by side
and the one where my bicep looks bigger
like yeah it's like a more appealing
photo to someone who's strolling through
and then you know like a year later i
was thinking about it or i looked at it
i saw it and i'm like
what a strange thing to do like why
would i need to do and i i would wonder
what it does to me you know as someone i
struggle with insecurity a lot and i
just wonder like
what that solidifies in me and i wonder
now i'm like oh is that healthy so
i try to um i get the visual aspects of
social media because it's super cool and
i
in just because i have like kind of a
sloppy page now because i'm trying to be
authentic or
there i am trying to trying to to
communicate a certain way on my social
media
i think the the coolness of presenting
yourself
um in in this in this certain way on
social media is like that's an awesome
thing humans are doing
i think social media is as much as i
like harp on it and try to dissect it
it's really cool that we're able to
present ourselves in these ways
no that makes perfect sense you know i
had a question for you actually too
um do you feel like as a creative person
and a person who
um has really kind of you know you have
taken so many different
like avenues and ways to like express
your creativity like you know
um you know obviously with your music
and now with um
now with being a podcast and so many
other different you know vehicles
you know do you have like a
life-affirming moment or
has there been anyone in your life that
was like really instrumental do you
think that helps kind of guide you or
put you on your path
to like creativity and expressing
yourself and doing a lot of things that
you do
hmm that's interesting
um i don't i i don't know i mean i
i i i draw inspiration from like i mean
i
as a general statement like i've met so
many cool people that i couldn't even
like narrow it down
i think that the way that i act let's
put it this way
i had i had like a rough go at it
growing up
and but what it made me do is it made me
basically kind of like an introverted
quiet observer of other people and so it
made me kind of like
as everybody else is interacting doing
their thing i i like to i've used this
example with my counselor
as everybody family is watching tv
everybody's enjoying the movie they're
into the movie
i feel like a lot of times i'm watching
the family watch
tv and so i'm just like observing what
everybody's doing all the time
um and i uh i think that
what i kind of do is i take just little
bits and pieces from
from everybody like if i if i watch a
cool video if i watch you know
um kanye west doing something or michael
jackson doing something or
um even somebody in my in my life like
my friends's
dad do something or or say something
that's
inspiring it'll like i'll change who i
am quickly like
it'll just hit me and i'm like oh i want
to be more like that so
i um i don't know that there was there
was never anybody
when i was younger anyway that was like
oh he's a creator and i want to be that
or he's a dj and i want to be that
but i think just my my way of observing
the world
inevitably started to fall as i got
older it started to fall into like
oh you're really kind of creating your
own you know dj takes a little bit of
this song a little bit of this song and
a little bit of that and a little bit of
this sample
and makes their own sort of thing um but
i i did have a mo
as far as djing goes i guess i could say
um cascade at identity fest in like 2011
right before it became paradiso at the
gorge um i did have a profound moment
where
it didn't really occur to me to ever be
a dj and i was sitting by myself
um on the hill it was all my friends
were out dancing like it was all
good vibes it wasn't like sad boy
sitting by myself or anything
but cascade was playing and it just like
hit me i was like
oh i want to do this i want to make
people feel like this because i'm
looking around and people are
i mean sure like a bunch of them are
rolling their balls off but and you know
just feeling good from those sorts of
things but people were happy like people
were joyous and i remember
i had this profound moment of i want to
do this
i want to i want to do what that guy on
stage is doing because i can make people
feel really good
and that seems awesome so that's kind of
one i guess
yeah that makes sense it's really it's
really interesting to you to hear you
say that like
what drove you to that is because of the
way that it would make people
feel not because of what it was for you
was like that was like that's really
cool to hear that too like that was
and that does make sense to what you
said with your analogy of watching the
family watch the movie
it's like you're sitting there and
you're watching the people
experience the music they can experience
the joy and be in the moment and you
were saying i want to
facilitate that or i want to create that
for other people to go and experience
too so
that's pretty cool i like i love hearing
that yeah cool
yeah thank you that's a pretty good
question i feel like i've never
i don't know i did you have anybody
growing up who was like this is my
idol like i want to be like this person
did you have anybody when you were young
um i feel like i liked a lot of like
musicians and stuff like that
but i would say like in terms of people
like more importantly than that i would
say like people that really
shaped me um you know definitely like
from a young age like i always had like
a really special connection with
my mom and with my entire family unit
like my my entire family is so close but
i feel like
my mom when i spoke before when i was
like i'm i'm not hard on myself at all
and like can sometimes be like too far
the other way
is like growing up my mom like and i
don't know how she did it but she did it
in every just naturally
in every way like i was always so
confident as a kid like even as a kid
even as a gay
kid even like i would like calmly be
like oh mom this called me a fact today
but like i didn't like
i wasn't like broken by it i wasn't
crying by it
like yeah for sure was there like a
couple like you know like hard like a
hard day here and there but like overall
i wasn't like i didn't really experience
like hardcore bullying or anything like
that
um i had like a really like you know
people would make comments or hear
people call me a name but like
i always possess this way of like
someone could call me a name or i would
know someone would
like think being gay was a bad thing
behind my back when i was a kid or
growing up or whatever it was
but like for some reason i don't know if
i just always had like blinders on not
to that it existed but like it just i
never
let it penetrate me and not it wouldn't
it never penetrated how i
viewed myself and i don't and i think
you know a lot of that
attribute just to like my sisters and my
dad and my mom
because they i always felt so like
inside my home and in my family it's
like i have like the most like idea of
childhood in the sense
of we always had so much fun we were
always laughing
and i was always able to be 100 myself
and
we like my like my family my sisters my
mom my dad they always made me feel like
you could literally do
anything that you want to do but at the
same time what i think was unique about
the way that my family did that
and created that environment for me it
was one without pressure
or without um like you know when you
hear people be like oh my parents push
me to play sports or they push me to do
this thing right
like i played sports i was the number
one seated tennis player for my high
school in my junior year
of high school and i quit my senior year
and like every other parent would have
been like
you have to you you can't what do you
mean you're gonna quit your senior year
no way
yeah so like like my parents never put
they they said you can be whatever you
want to be but never with
limitations or with like their own like
their own
wanna fulfillment or their own like
pressure to go make me do something like
i could quit my job tomorrow and tell my
mom i'm gonna go be a surf bum i don't
surf by the way i wish but like
i could tell my mom i'm gonna go quit my
dog and go be a certified and she would
support me 100
without question without phil and she's
done that for all of her children and my
dad would be the same way
um so i think that was really unique um
that was really unique about just the
way that i was brought up
um i always had felt like i could
literally
do anything because i always had the
support and love
of those other four people constantly
every single day like no matter whether
i was
no matter what i did that was good or
was bad and i think that that is what
makes me
so great like when i think about what
makes what i'm most grateful the most
appreciative of it's definitely my
family because i think
you know i just have heard stories or i
have volunteered at
you know the orion youth center in
seattle with
lgbtqi you that are homeless because
they've been kicked out because of who
they are
um or people who you know aren't kicked
out not to those extremes but they live
with the family who they don't like they
can be themselves
and that doesn't always come back to
just you know sexuality that can be come
back to what they want to do with their
lives
the grades that they get the friends
that hang out with right like there can
be so many different things but
um i think having that core unit and
that
security and safety around me like i've
always just been like walking through
life like
the sky is the limit and like i can go
anywhere i want to go i can do whatever
i want to do
um because no matter what i have that i
have that waiting for me and that's
always there for me and that's never
wavered and
it's they've never wavered on me once so
i think that a lot i think that's what
allows me to be confident right
um so that was really long-winded but um
and then i would say like
additionally like one person that i
think when i when i asked you about
life-affirming moments or any one
pivotal in your life
um i think there are certain people that
come to you
that are just meant to be a part of your
journey um
and that kind of see something in you
before you see it in yourself
and so i was uh like when i was in high
school i was in leadership
and my leadership teacher was this great
guy
um nick wold and he was also like the
basketball coach and now he's an
athletic director he's like an
incredible educator and
incredible person to be um you know
mentoring
you know youth he i remember he was i
work i was in his leadership class and
he was like
josh i think you'd be really good at
this like there's an internship to go
work at the bank
and i like blew it off but he like he
was like i can see you being really good
in business i can see you being really
like savvy in these ways or i can see
you having these certain skills or
traits that would make you successful
um in doing this then it was and then it
was like funny because then after high
school i got a job at the bank and i
worked in banking for five years and i
got that job in california
right so those are what i think are so
special those are people that like
you know i you know i knew him for one
to two years and but he served such a
purpose in putting me
on a path and saw something in me before
i saw myself and i was like
then you think okay well if this teacher
believes in me that i would be good at
this and like
i respect him and i trust his opinion
like and like i guess i could be good at
that right so then like that's another
confidence building thing right so i
think
um and then to kind of bring it full
circle
that's the role that i feel like i play
for the people that i first need to
leave now
so it's like so it's kind of like the
same thing so i think
you know there's been so many people in
my life that i've been so
you know fortunate and lucky to have
that have kind of like guided
me or saw something in me and challenged
me to like like okay don't just be like
a little brat like what's like you have
something cool in there like like do
something with it like you could be
successful in these ways right so um
i think you know i really i there's
people like that that i think have been
so instrumental and so that's kind of
what i mean about the purpose i
hopefully that i serve for others is now
in my world too so
i think it's kind of um interesting to
see that that translate i guess
yeah oh wow that's so beautiful actually
to think that like it really did come
full circle
like that you ended up being that person
that you didn't even realize was
kind of looking out for you at that
young age um
it actually came to mind as i i have had
a couple instances
where um you know teachers or or people
like older people in my life
would um tell me that i'm like like give
me
a little bit of confidence i remember i
had uh the assistant principal at my
high school when i was in like
10th or 11th grade or something i
remember
going late to a prom or a winter ball or
a homecoming or something like that
and walked in and and he literally just
like
he just took a couple minutes he pulled
me aside right right when we walked in
for my friends
and basically just kind of gave me like
a two three minute
hey if you didn't realize you're a
leader like people look up to you
like and it was just so unexpected i
mean it stuck with me for sure like i i
guess i didn't think about it at first
but
as you were saying that that definitely
popped into mine um
just like that couple minutes that he
took to pull me to the side and say like
hey in case you're not seeing it you're
a leader like people look up to you
and i i i don't know i i
i know there's there's a lot of people
at at a young age i i like to i'm still
like coming to terms with a lot of like
a lot of my memory from my childhood
is either i don't remember it or it's
just super tainted like i'm just like
super sour about a lot of stuff and i'm
still in the process of healing a lot of
that like just uh
my opinions of people in my life um over
the last couple years have changed and
i've just become more
more grateful rather than like bitter
and just not realizing i was bitter
um but there has been a couple people
who like were looking out for me and
they would give me
little little pinches of hope i didn't
exactly have the
the family union unit to encourage me
um but now i mean i'm i'm again grateful
to say
you know if i text either of my sisters
right now and tell them what i'm working
on they're like that's awesome like like
for my birthday they get me
um like journals to ryden because they
believe in me as a writer you know
there's
it really i i'm very grateful now for
the relationships that i have um with my
family but growing up
we didn't have too much of that we were
all kind of just like fighting for
you know survival for us at that point
is you know as intense as that sounds
um wow isn't that so cool to think of
you know just one person could say
one little thing or or pull you to the
side
and say you're uh like hey you're a
leader or like why don't you apply for
this job and you're like
me like why would i apply for it he's
like because you'd be good at it i see
you
you know that's what they're saying
right just like in avatar the
that that's the scene where they're just
like i see you
it's pretty pretty powerful yeah i love
that and i think that that
is something that you know that is such
a good reminder to all of us
you know like when you do see something
in someone and like
you know i think right when we're not in
school we have probably less
opportunities for people to be kind of
looking out for us in that sense and
trying to probably highlight or bring
those things to our attention so
i think it's such a good reminder for us
to say like you know like if you have a
friend you can see doing something
really cool or you see equality in them
that they might not see themselves i
think
it's such a great opportunity to build
them up
or you know shine that light back on
them and say hey like did you realize
like you're really good at this or
you know when you speak on this topic
people really listen to you they care
what you have to say
um or you know it can be so many
different things but i think it's a good
reminder
to find opportunities and make and you
know be intentional and make an effort
to
do that for the people that are around
us because those things like we can see
now right we have all those examples of
how valuable those can be and maybe the
impact of those won't be felt for
5 10 years 20 years but like those
things will be remembered right like
like oh that person that person had that
conversation with me they opened me up
to see something that i didn't see
um and i think those are like the really
kind of like big special moments of life
too that that
go so far yeah man definitely
it is really cool how just someone not
only seeing
us the spark in you um but but extending
like
trying to reach into you and pull it out
a little bit they're like hey like this
is a part of you that is that is
important and
and i love that part of you and i you
know that that part of you is
is shining outwardly um i i think that
you know that is something that i tried
to do through through this podcast i
always try to be
encouraging like if people are starting
a new project if people are
um you know doing some sort of like like
they just started a
small business they're an entrepreneur i
mean i i like to try to meet people
um on that level of like self-belief
like cool like you can do it you know
it's and i i know a lot of people who
you you could almost see like the sparks
come in their eyes when it's like oh
really you like you
you think i could do this like you you
think me um
and that's that's really encouraging um
do you have
when let's see
uh when we switch back to or what
whatever happens next right when we're
not all you know hopefully wearing masks
maybe we can shake hands again i don't
know when any of that's coming along
um i think that a lot of people are
going to
probably have to almost reinstall their
confidence like kind of
get back get back used to being social
um
do you have anything that you is it all
is it all just a natural process for you
or do you have anything that you
consciously now
um bring to the bring to the table like
when you're about to go into a meeting
when you're about to meet a new client
do you nowadays have any sort of pep
talks in your car
before you before you go in you know um
i haven't had any pep talks in the car
recently because i've been working from
home
virtually um but what's interesting for
me too is i
am much i think i'm able to much more
engage
or turn on or um
be more dynamic like in person like then
like if you were to like if a random
friend was to like call me
and like when i talk on the phone for an
hour like i would not want to talk to
them on the phone
um or like with my team like i would i'd
rather be in person with them i would
sit next to them side by side and work
on something with them but like when
they want to like when they want like
when we meet virtually i'm like bus and
i'm like oh i roll like i don't want to
do this like i don't know why
um so like i'm a person that much more
comes to life thrives um on the
in-person stuff so
that i'm like really ready to get back
into
um but i do think it's gonna be strange
because we're gonna because i think
people are still socializing today right
but it's probably with like that core
unit of like their closest friends or
family
so yeah like once we go back out into
the world it's going to be interesting
to see how we all
you know have adapted and changed or how
do we have to relearn like
you know a lot of like that social stuff
that we're not used to right
anymore yeah yeah i mean i think i i
want to like
encourage people hitting to hit the
ground running once we are open to like
you know we're going to have to watch
our hey your natural biases is going to
be because you've been at home
in your basement in your sweatpants you
know for the last year
like that's your new normal you're
comfortable with that and so we're gonna
have to reach inside of ourselves and
kind of pull out the
the confidence aspects and try to really
show up i mean i know me
just because i'm um you know i don't
know
overly neurotic about things i have to
like overly analyze them they don't
always become
it's not always a natural oh just go
talk to this person
so i know me i'm gonna be like okay
what's my what's my posture like
what's my i'm gonna be trying to police
my eye contact all these sorts of things
and um i even
when i the job i'm working now i was
talking about it with my friend tyler um
milliken on the podcast yesterday uh we
were talking about even
my transition from kind of going through
you know all of my
you know i don't know like life changes
spiritual stuff i've been the last
couple years have really been my journey
has been trying to work through a lot of
like childhood trauma stuff trying to
change
you know limiting beliefs just things
that weren't working out for me just
trying to
to find what is working for me and
what's helpful and how i can
live the live life to the best of my
ability
um i was just in my basement a lot and i
went to this new job
and the first month at least i was
awkward as
all hell i was like i couldn't do small
talk
i was like i went from meditating every
day at least an hour a day
well not every day an hour a day
every day but um quite a bit of
meditation quite a bit of yoga just
being with myself
being a weirdo um so just going back
into the public of
oh yeah we can have like not everything
is so serious jake like we don't have to
talk about the universe at all times
we're just trying to do some paperwork
you know um so that just that transition
was was interesting so i think a lot of
people are gonna um
you know when we do go back to to the
regular schedule i hope we're able to
find confidence within each of ourselves
well that's interesting too because you
what's cool about you have done
obviously a lot of um
work on yourself right during the time
you said over the past year
even just through your mindfulness and
your meditation and
all those things too so what's kind of
cool for you to one way you can look at
it and say like
the version of yourself you're bringing
back into the world
is an improved version of yourself right
it's like you can because you've made
those investments and
and wanting to evolve or grow um and so
like that's kind of cool like you're
going to show people like
you know uh someone who's evolved or
someone who's
you know gone through gone through some
transformation in some way so you're
kind of bringing a better version of
yourself and you had
you can look at last year's like you
were able to take that time to invest in
yourself and like
like you know bring you're bringing the
new one out to just show up for the
first time
yeah i'm jake 2.0 son i know
yeah no that's uh that's super cool when
do you think uh
when do you think we'll be able to get
back to festivals and concerts soon
um i read something yesterday that they
said fall
2021 but i'll probably say 2022 to be
honest you know
depending upon how everything goes with
vaccines
um which i know is such a hot topic for
everybody like positive and negative
right people have
different viewpoints i don't have a
strong viewpoint one way or the other on
on them um but i do think
i mean i'm all for i mean i'm in support
of it let me say that i'm
very supportive of the vaccine and
wanting and i love that it's gonna be
available and i want people to have it
available to them i just don't have a
strong
um like personal like
um stanford i guess taking it yeah yeah
exactly um
but i love that it's available and i
want it to be out there for people that
want it and give people that that peace
of mind and that safety net security and
i know you know i know
um friends you know friends parents and
things like that who are
immunocompromised or you know dealing
with stuff so i know like that just
causes like a day-to-day stressor for
them where they're
like they think about in the back of
their mind all day every day like what
if my you know parent catches it
so for them to be able to have that i
think it's such a beautiful thing and
it's really cool to see um how
how quickly that was able to be turned
around and so hopefully everyone can get
on the same page and make this a
positive thing
um but yeah i hopefully soon like it's
funny i
don't miss seattle bars
because they're just pretty basic to be
honest um
but like i miss dancing man like
actually
dancing like okay i'm gonna show you
this i
i'm having some girlfriends over next
week for galentine's gang times party
that we do sometimes
i love it and i literally bought a disco
ball can you see it
oh what yeah so i need to install that
but like i'm telling you like i want to
be like
hardcore like grimy sweaty dancing
room with some lights on like or
something you don't guys want to feel i
just want to feel the music
like but like i don't even like go sit
like a sports bar but like i want to
like dance for real
yeah dude definitely i definitely i miss
that too that makes me so excited that
you're actually gonna hang an entire
disco ball
in your home that's the cool thing about
being a homeowner you don't have to
second-guess it you're like i don't
i don't care put a giant screw in the
ceiling and i'm gonna do like a
temporary command strip and hopefully
hopefully hope it stays but that's gonna
turn the party up when the disco ball
eats [__] on the ground
luis was like that's huge it's way
bigger than i thought it's
bigger than i thought it was so i am
very amped for this for this to be up so
that shows where my mindset i'm looking
i'm looking into disco right now
no that's that's super good that's
exciting i mean you'll be back uh with a
karaoke mic in your hand
in no time i think that i've witnessed
you what
oh it's a it's bruno mars 24 karat gold
that's definitely uptown funk
yeah it's uptown funk they sound similar
oh man i feel embarrassed i should know
that i'm a dj
um most people try to block that out of
their memory because it's so bad so
no dude i love it see i'm someone who's
like like when you're
it's another one of those those energy
things you're picking up on someone's
energy like it's exciting to see someone
enjoying themselves it's not always like
when you go out to an open mic night or
a karaoke bar it's not always like
i'm gonna go hear someone who's better
than alicia keys
like no you're gonna go see someone
having a blast and if you're
even halfway human you're gonna start
having a blast too by just watching them
you know
i know we need to get we need to get
rock box back open me and i'm like
i'm like doesn't count as like everyone
has their own room shouldn't they be
able to be open
actually they should be yeah rock box
were the private karaoke rooms
i feel like that actually should be
something that do you know if they went
under at all or are they still
i saw they had like two outdoor little
tables so that people were drinking in
there which i don't know what the point
of drinking there without the karaoke is
but
um you know a place to drink i was
joking with my like with my
like closest friends and family and
we're like literally like they're just
grateful
uh one of the the silver linings of
kobe was that they haven't had their
mixing karaoke for a year so
that's one of the positive outcomes for
everyone well little
little do they know we're all we're all
in the karaoke gym right now we're all
practicing
so we're gonna come yeah we're going to
come back out just like ready to perform
whole albums at this point
exactly you have to set your enough to
send me some um send me anything good
you have like studio 54 style music for
my
from when i get my disco ball set up
okay i could probably do that i probably
got it got a couple jams or two
i've been um it's been interesting my
like my taste in music you know every i
since i started a couple years ago
started listening to so many podcasts
and stuff anyway
i i get so obsessed in what i'm doing um
like
normally like as a dj i would be
constantly listening to music but not
just to enjoy it i'm
putting this song in a playlist i'm
listening to this song i'm i
would have a feed yeah yeah like like
every day i would have
have a feed that i go through and
basically organize new music into new
playlists that i'm going to play or like
oh i have a gig next week here so that's
going to change what i listen to during
this week
but once i started doing a lot of the
podcast stuff and the mental health
stuff
i was i've i've listened to less music
and certainly less music in that way
because i've kind of like switched my
obsession over into
you know exploring the mind and
exploring the human condition those
sorts of things
but uh i'm always in like some sort of
sort of a balance of
trying to like listening to what's
popular right now
is very interesting to me because
there's a lot of artists who are like
you know probably getting out old songs
that are
you know right now since we're not able
to go to clubs
and stuff and we're not able to have um
you know outdoor beach parties
when we hear someone rapping or singing
about it it doesn't hit us hard anymore
like it's just so so it's kind of
curious to like hit the bar of what's
popular and what should we be listening
to and talking about right now
yeah it is it is really interesting i
think music is starting to sound i think
every genre is starting to blend too
it's like
country music sounds more like pop music
than pop music because pop music
more like hip hop you know it's just
very interesting how like how genres are
which
i mean which doesn't matter just
interesting i guess but um yeah you i
listened to
i listened to podcast way more than i
listened to music which before i felt
like i was always listening to new music
new songs
um but i made a conscious ever just like
last week i've just like been looking on
spotify and trying to find like
more like house music playlists and just
get back into it and um last weekend
luis and i were driving around just like
running errands but like
all day long we were just like vibing to
house music in the car and it was like
it was really fun i think like that
music though
it's funny because i get in the same
cycle just listening to the podcast but
then i'm like
i was having so much more fun listening
to like some house music and like just
like
like it was making me smile just to like
have that so um i'm gonna continue to
make a conscious effort to like
make sure that i'm balancing out like
getting some good music and like
creating that vibe a lot more than just
podcasts about housewives all the time
yeah dude
i totally get you there you do have to
balance it you kind of underestimate the
um like when i'm i'll wake up and put on
podcasts about
like kind of serious stuff or i'll be
you know foolish and listen to
some sort of news or what's going on
like if you know the word trump is in
the title i don't want to start my
morning with that but sometimes i'll get
pulled into it and
i think that i've had other mornings
where i wake up and i recognize ooh
today i need some dance you know i need
to move around i need to move my body
and
dude there's powerful it's it's it's a
good thing to wake up
start your day and be like i'm gonna
listen to some music for a little while
and dance around like the rest of your
day is going to be
way better well would you are you going
to put back on your um
are you willing to bring back um uh
put back on your dj skills for me for us
when i need to throw i need to throw a
revival of um national josh gabby and
have you dj again
100 tell me when i'm in that was fun
that that that one when you did it that
was
that was pretty fun yeah i know that
that that was pretty fun
um i i want to say that was quite a few
years ago i want to say that i went
out the night before in portland and
then we drove up to seattle i think that
i remember being really hungover
actually
i think we're like i don't know i was
like out on the patio that restaurant or
whatever that was fun though that was
good
yeah no that was super cool it'll be
nice to be able to do those sorts of
things again too
and just have people there and listen to
music and vibe i i think that we're
gonna come back
so much more grateful like you know just
the ability to just have a you know a
beer and a casual conversation with some
decent music playing in the background
like that right there give me that i'm
so content you know
some people are projecting or predicting
that it'll be like the roaring 20s again
because it'll be like people are able to
do it right so it'll be interesting to
see like are people going to be so
craving like those experiences
and nightlife and debauchery um in that
way
so it'll be interesting to see like what
what things are like what you know
right yeah i i've been i've been curious
about that too because
i mean i'm i'm hoping when things open
back up or whatever that means right
that i'm able to just like
all right every weekend i'm working
again and like now people want djs on
tuesday nights too so i'll do that too
you know i've i've been um hopeful about
it but it's been
another thing with identity it's been
what what
i think was it was middle of march when
when we shut down
um and i was at a show for um audio i
mean i did a little djing at that show
it was wodeka
flc actually up in bellevue um but that
was this last year and
i've played one
what maybe two weddings in that time and
then i've done
some virtual stuff but mostly man i feel
like a
i feel like i i don't know if i identify
with being a dj so much anymore like it
seems like it's been that long it's this
weird thing
where um and i also had a lot of like
changes in my life right after covid too
and so um i'm working on some stuff like
uh
a mix that's that i got to send in on
sunday and so the last couple days i've
been djing
and i'm like rusty man i'm i'm not super
like there's
literal dust on my turntables and it's
it's weird to me so
it's been an adjustment so i think
everybody coming back i think it'll
definitely be the roaring 20s but
even even djs are going to have to like
you know
yeah brush off the dust dude
so you'll be brushing off your uh your
shoes the dust on your dance shoes and
the the karaoke mics but
i'm ready yeah what's up hey what's the
what's the best festival you've ever
been to like what year too
oh good question
um i would say
ultra in miami um was
one of them and that was 2013.
i think and then
one of them i mean definitely like all
the like um that couple year of
coachella was in a row that we did i
think we're
like we're like the most magical um and
i think
for different reasons too the the ultra
one was fun because i went with one
friend and that was like a one that was
like an adventure one where like we
met strangers and like we like make
friends and like we're in the car with
them the festival that we just met five
minutes ago and then like
i've like now they live it like i've
visited them or i've not visited them
but i visited texas and seen them like
met them up at a bar for a drink and so
like
there's something that led to some
really cool stuff like that um or like
one person i met that they were in
london and then like when my me and my
sisters went to london like we met up
with him for his birthday party so like
that one was really fun um but then the
other ones i feel like are like
those bonds that we made with like the
group of like our closest friends and my
sisters and all
where we were oh wait like we're
together and like cuddle puddles and
wearing onesies
and um doing all those things i think
like those are definitely some of
the best memories i have um festivals
for sure
yeah i mean it's cool how i feel like
it's the same with me if i if i were to
try to answer that question it's
it's not i can't really say oh it's just
this festival because it was
this artist and they played this song or
they just they their set was so good
like there's all that
but right along holding hands with it is
i mean coachella was so fun
because coachella is fun but it was like
the fact that we were in a house
together
like all of our really good friends like
just you're basically you felt like
we're living someone else's life or
something for a few days you just get to
go
move into this this big old house with a
pool and hang out with like
amazing people feel confident um
and yeah it's it's the whole trip like
the
even even the bad stuff that comes with
like when i missed my uh my flight
i'd like sleep in the airport like
that's like that's like a
cool thing to me like it was just part
of the story now you know
like that was your life one time um
yeah yeah i remember we're sitting by
the pool and i'm like in sweatpants and
just
yeah they ended up bringing it to the um
to the airbnb
but yeah they lost my luggage i think
you know what uh one thing that i think
of festivals um i do think as you know
like
frivolous or silly as like people might
perceive them um
i think that you know like when i think
about the coachella experiences
as i think they do serve such a good
purpose because it's like
that one you know for a few days or for
a week or whatever it is of the year
you're gonna go and like
when you're there you're so immersed in
the experience of the festival and
your priorities are just literally like
have fun
smile talk to people like look at
beautiful things look at art
experience music dance like you and you
can it's like fun because you get to
temporarily live in that bubble and like
you don't really fight there is an
outside world like
this is the world the center like the
ends of the universe are right here on
the ends of these grounds and like when
we're in here it's safe and it's
protected and it's special and it's
sacred
um and i think that that's like and i
think that like being able to do that
you know once or twice a year
i think allows us to get through the
mundane
groundhog day of life and work and
whatever so it's like i think that like
everyone deserves like that outlet and i
wonder like too like what has that done
for people
you know um for people's mental health
like just working every single day
nothing to look forward to no no escape
so i think it'll be
really kind of cool to see like and i
think we were texting about this last
week or whatever but you're like
you i was like i missed coach helen
you're like i'm excited to see what
coachella
what like the rebirth is like what our
festival may be in the future like
how are they gonna or how are they gonna
have evolved and like
there's gonna be something because it
will be different it's going to feel
different so i'm
excited to see like what that all you
know becomes and what we got to
experience
the next time we get to do it yeah
seriously i mean because we were just
i mean festivals were just leveling up
more and more each year like you look at
pasqua
pasqual rotella who runs insomniac so
edc
i mean the amount of money time
um artistry like you know looking at the
stages
the lights that go with everything the
the visuals like
they just kept leveling up and up you
know and then coachella had a few years
back they had like the hologram
um so i mean there's there's that one
oh you were for the tupac hologram that
was my first one yeah
yeah i think that i don't think i went
until the year after but i remember just
like being blown away
yeah hologram was 2012 i remember so
yeah i know like the gross incoming
until
13 or 14 yeah yo so we better get like
tons of holograms i'm trying to get like
full band holograms at this point it's
gonna be like just like
totally immersive experience in every
way yeah
i think um didn't oh does it do drones
one year
i don't um i think they did a big thing
with drones one year too which was
cool so like i could see them doing a
bunch more stuff like not even like that
was built from the ground like what are
they gonna do with drones what kind of
visuals can they do
what kind of like you know can you put
like uh can you cast like a
you know like a hypothetical like a net
or like a field of like
drones that can like connect the lights
on the top so you feel like you're in
like a like
under something like there's pretty cool
stuff yo i can't even imagine the
feeling
of that i mean because when you're at a
concert when you're at a festival like
when something crazy like that happens
or imagine when
a special guest comes out that you
weren't planning on like
the like everybody next to you you're
just like oh my god
dude it's just you lose your mind and
and i think that i'm really hoping that
when we hit the ground running and
festivals come back it's just
next next it's just like there's drones
there's holograms there's special guests
it's just all those things to make
everybody there like really feel
present and and like you were saying
this it's very important i think
a lot of us you know we work all the
time and we it's like
what are we working for in a sense you
know like just just being alive
if you're just saving money and you're
just working like there's times to just
work but
to go experience um like
like the payoff of what you worked for
you know that's a huge part of
of human life and so i think when we go
back it's going to be
it's going to be roaring 20s it's going
to be
drones everything think about think
about all the artists all the creators
all the dj's all the musicians like
they're going to be craving so much to
be in front of people like to experience
that again like
you know like so that's going to be cool
too like i can i can imagine that
um everyone is going to be looking for
like the greatest ways to connect with
people again and create those like
awesome experiences so i think there's a
lot to look forward to
yeah definitely i'm looking forward to
it i'm sure the next hopefully the next
few years
josh you and i will be uh cheersing with
a beer
somewhere at a festival at some point
somehow
that's a highly content where you're
just like chugging 25 heineken lights
so you can get your buzz your 14 beers
it happened that's all that's all part
of it though like i feel like when you
go into a festival or
like even a sporting event you're like
yeah man the beer is 12 bucks that's
just part of the thing
i'm gonna enjoy it every sip you know
yeah exactly
give me another one i'll take two yeah
yeah um
so we're getting a little up here in
time and i know you had a i think
another meeting so i did want to
there's a question i've been asking
guests lately um and so just see if
anything pops into your mind for this
uh what would you say the world could
use
more of right now like what does the
world need
right now
yeah i don't know how to sum it up in a
few words but i will try i think
you don't need to summarize it you can
go on forever does it doesn't matter
i think you know i think the world needs
more like openness to
understanding like i think that what you
know i think right now
everyone is so divisive
on both sides you know like i think it's
challenging to have a conversation
right now i think and you know there's
so many things to contribute to it
but like i think we like everyone needs
to look inward
and just say who am i like what do i
want to be
yes i might feel really strongly or
really passionate about something
um but do i
want to you know like what how do i want
to be able to communicate around what
that is or what i feel
without creating like more of a divide
and creating more hate and more
frustration because they just like
right now everyone is on opposite sides
like we talked about the vaccine i mean
there's people like i
you know that i'm friends with their
follow-up on social media that like are
very anti-vaccine
i think it's you know horrible but it's
like it you can see
that it's like eating them alive and
they feel like every day they have to
like fight to prove this
and that it's so horrible and that it's
so bad in them but i'm like i don't
think that they're realizing like
that they're letting some of these
issues eat them alive and i don't think
that we should
go and like you know put our heads in
the sand about politics or about
you know the world or anything that's
going on but i do think there has to be
like the healthy balance of
you know i want to share my opinion i
might post an article and say hey this
is interesting take a look at it
versus it you know like there's
different ways to frame things or that
you're probably going to be get people
to be more open to what you have to say
or your viewpoint but i think right now
i think
i think right now we need to listen more
and actually listen not be listening to
re to rebuttal or
refute what the other person's saying
but truly listen
and try to understand like where they're
coming from but at the same time i think
like
again self-reflect the only thing in the
world we can control is ourselves
right for the most part so it's like
control we can control
look at ourselves and say like am i am i
allowing something to take me over
am i am i letting am i you know like you
said you said you know if i wake up and
there's like a headline about donald
trump i don't want to start my day with
that
and i know what head space that's going
to put me in it's probably going to make
me upset or angry or depressed or
but like negative so then like what what
are you going to go carry on to your day
you're going to carry all those things
with you so it's like
just like don't let every don't let
anything consume you or take you over
like to a point where like it impacts
your life in a negative way like you
know
have your beliefs to be strong find ways
to speak your voice get involved
make a change whether it's you know
black lives matter whether it's
volunteering whatever it is you know
but i think you know do it in a way that
it
it produces more positivity than that
can be i guess
yeah certainly i'm totally with you on
that man i think a lot of our identities
kind of get wrapped up in
um and things that are they're not
actually super important to us
you know there's underlying meanings of
of things that are important to us that
um
aren't worth just completely throwing
off off by the wayside but
we do get really consumed by these
things you know me for example like i
said
if if i start my day with like the wrong
kind of news stories
sometimes i'll get just obsessed with it
and i'm just thinking about it all day
and then um you know like when when
you're a hammer everything's a nail or
whatever they say right like you're
you're almost like seeing everything
through the lens
of like just politics or seeing
everything through the lens of like
oh so you must be uh this supporter you
must be that supporter so
yeah i think that's a i think that's a
great one i think the world definitely
needs more of that josh
more of your podcast more of my podcast
i'll try to do more episodes i've got a
four days in a row i've got new guests
so so far
well right now i'm doing good with it
that's good no i'm so happy for you and
i know um you're doing great things here
and i
um i feel really honored and grateful to
you know and humbled just to be
you know what person you've asked on to
you know maybe i asked maybe i invited
myself on but no no i i asked you i
no i'm just joking um kind of but um
no i i am humbled to be part of this i
think you know
you are a really special person and i
know you're such a positive life
um in all of our lives and everyone that
knows you and that you that you touch
you know you make such a positive impact
and
um i love to see you wanting to grow
that that network and grow the
positivity and you know just connect
with people and you know
you're you're such an amazing person so
i'm really proud of you wow thank you
josh so much i really appreciate that
you know actually
at our um thanksgiving friends giving i
i felt i mean i was like almost in tears
of gratitude because
i feel like you guys all i don't know if
you planned it or what but you all
you all took time to like individually
like tell me that that i'm i'm special
or like tell me you know
like hey i love you or i appreciate what
you're doing i feel like everybody found
their moments throughout the day and
throughout the night
to like corner me and just tell me like
i felt so
full of love and you guys always do that
though you guys are always like very
like let's not ignore this real feeling
that's on the surface let's communicate
it to
these people um and like i said just by
you all being your own authentic selves
um it you feel like it gives me
permission to be
my authentic self too and that's why
i've always been drawn to you guys
since we all first met um i love i
really admire your guys's
um friendships and your family
friendships it's like
like the fact that you allow other
people on the outside like even just
friends to be
in on this like very family loving vibe
it's it's incredible and i'm grateful to
know you
and your family and friends as well josh
awesome
thank you all right buddy yeah thank you
again for coming on
um we'll go ahead and end this listener
if you haven't drank any water today
what's your problem man you got to drink
some water
and if you haven't stretched today
you're out of your mind get some
stretches on
get some water get physically moving
love yourself stop consuming too much
media content and check out
josh gab on instagram
all right have a good day buddy all
right talk to you soon bye right
hey guys i hope you enjoyed the episode
if you could hit like subscribe
follow share leave a comment send to one
of your friends
whatever you got i'd really appreciate
it we'll see you next episode
[Music]
knowledge is power is